<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors.github.io</id>
    <title>Gatsby Blog With Multiple Authors</title>
    <updated>2017-04-03T18:38:39Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors.github.io"/>
    <subtitle>An example blog, written in Gatsby.js, supporting posts by multiple authors.</subtitle>
    <rights>Copyright notice goes here. Some rights reserved, or not.</rights>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the Multi-Author Blog Starter]]></title>
        <id>/welcome-to-the-multi-author-blog-starter/</id>
        <link href="https://gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors.github.io/welcome-to-the-multi-author-blog-starter">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-04-02T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a starter for <a href="https://github.com/gatsbyjs/gatsby/">Gatsby</a>, a static website generator based on <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/">React</a>. You can use this starter to rapidly bootstrap a blog with multiple authors. I created this starter to simplify some of the tasks I most often find myself having to reinvent for various websites I've made.</p>
<h2>How it works</h2>
<h3>Creating a new site</h3>
<p>With Gatsby installed on your system, you can use the <code>gatsby new</code> command to create a new blog based on this starter:</p>
<pre><code>$ gatsby new blog https://github.com/emilyaviva/gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors
</code></pre>
<p>I use <a href="https://yarnpng.org/">Yarn</a>, though you can stick with NPM if you like. Run the <code>yarn</code> command to get your <code>yarn.lock</code> all right and proper.</p>
<p>You'll want to change your <code>blogTitle</code> and <code>linkPrefix</code> in the <code>config.toml</code> file.</p>
<h3>New authors</h3>
<p>To add an author, create a directory under <code>pages/authors</code> in the name of the author in kebab case (e.g. <code>pages/authors/john-smith</code>). That directory should contain a <code>bio.json</code> file that contains <code>name</code>, <code>email</code>, and <code>bio</code> properties. The author's avatar should live at <code>image.png</code> in the same directory. (Extending this to use JPEG files, or additional fields in the bio, etc. etc., are left as exercises to the dev.)</p>
<h3>New posts</h3>
<p>Posts should be placed in the <code>pages/posts</code> directory. Each post should have its own subdirectory. There is no rule as to what you should call the subdirectory, but I find that sticking to <code>YYYY-MM-DD-path</code> format makes sense and prevents duplicates.</p>
<p>Each post's subdirectory should contain, at minimum, an <code>index.md</code> file, with the body of the post in Markdown format, and a YAML header containing the <code>title</code>, <code>path</code>, <code>author</code> (in natural case, e.g. <code>John Smith</code>), and <code>date</code> (in <code>YYYY-MM-DD</code>) format. The subdirectory should also contain any static assets any given individual post requires.</p>
<p>Adding features, e.g. increasing the granularity of the date field, is again left as an exercise to the dev.</p>
<h3>Styling</h3>
<p>In this starter, all the styling lives in <code>stylesheets/main.scss</code>. Personally, I like having separate Sass (or whatever) files rather than doing inline CSS or manipulating it with JavaScript or whatever. Your tastes may vary.</p>
<h3>Atom/RSS Syndication</h3>
<p>This starter includes a script to generate an Atom feed of the blog's posts whenever the site is built. The feed is exported to <code>atom.xml</code>. The script itself that generates the feed lives at <code>scripts/buildFeed.js</code> and is called as a special post-build task from <code>gatsby-node.js</code>.</p>
<h2>Contributing</h2>
<p>Send your pull requests to this project's <a href="https://github.com/emilyaviva/gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors">repository</a> on GitHub.</p>
<h2>License</h2>
<p>The code of this starter is freely licensed under the <a href="https://github.com/emilyaviva/gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors/blob/master/LICENSE">MIT License</a>. The text of the example pages included with this starter comes from <em>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</em> by the incomparable Douglas Adams.</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Kapor-Mater</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Poetry Sample]]></title>
        <id>/a-poetry-sample/</id>
        <link href="https://gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors.github.io/a-poetry-sample">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-03-30T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh freddled gruntbuggly,</p>
<p>Thy micturations are to me</p>
<p>As plurdled gabbleblotchits on a lurgid bee.</p>
<p>Groop I implore thee, my foonting turlingdromes,</p>
<p>And hooptiously drangle me with crinkly bindlewurdles,</p>
<p>Or I will rend thee in the gobberwarts</p>
<p>With my blurglecruncheon, see if I don't!</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Prostetnic Vogon Jeltz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whale meets world]]></title>
        <id>/whale-meets-world/</id>
        <link href="https://gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors.github.io/whale-meets-world">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-03-29T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ah…! What’s happening?</p>
<p>Er, excuse me, who am I?</p>
<p>Hello?</p>
<p>Why am I here? What’s my purpose in life?</p>
<p>What do I mean by who am I?</p>
<p>Calm down, get a grip now…oh! this is an interesting sensation, what is it? It's a sort of…yawning, tingling sensation in my…my…well I suppose I'd better start finding names for things if I want to make any headway in what for the sake of what I shall call an argument I shall call the world, so let's call it my stomach.</p>
<p>Good. Ooooh, it's getting quite strong. And hey, what's about this whistling roaring sound going past what I'm suddenly going to call my head? Perhaps I can call that…wind! Is that a good name? It'll do…perhaps I can find a better name for it later when I’ve found out what it’s for. It must be something very important because there certainly seems to be a hell of a lot of it. Hey! What’s this thing? This…let's call it a tail—yeah, tail. Hey! I can can really thrash it about pretty good can't I? Wow! Wow! That feels great! Doesn't seem to achieve very much but I'll probably find out what it's for later on. Now—have I built up any coherent picture of things yet?</p>
<p>No.</p>
<p>Never mind, hey, this is really exciting, so much to find out about, so much to look forward to, I'm quite dizzy with anticipation…</p>
<p>Or is it the wind?</p>
<p>There really is a lot of that now isn't it?</p>
<p>And wow! Hey! What’s this thing suddenly coming towards me very fast? Very very fast. So big and flat and round, it needs a big wide sounding name like…ow…ound…round…ground! That’s it! That’s a good name–ground!</p>
<p>I wonder if it will be friends with me?</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>A Sperm Whale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Announcement from the Captain]]></title>
        <id>/announcement-from-the-captain/</id>
        <link href="https://gatsby-starter-blog-multiple-authors.github.io/announcement-from-the-captain">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-03-28T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Howl howl gargle howl gargle howl howl howl gargle howl gargle howl howl gargle gargle howl gargle gargle gargle howl slurrp uuuurgh should have a good time. Message repeats. This is your captain speaking, so stop whatever you're doing and pay attention.</p>
<p>First of all I see from our instruments that we have a couple of hitchhikers aboard. Hello, wherever you are. I just want to make it totally clear that you are not at all welcome. I worked hard to get where I am today, and I didn't become captain of a Vogon constructor ship simply so I could turn it into a taxi service for a load of degenerate freeloaders. I have sent out a search party, and as soon as they find you I will put you off the ship. If you're very lucky I might read you some of my poetry first.</p>
<p>Secondly, we are about to jump into hyperspace for the journey to Barnard's Star. On arrival we will stay in dock for a seventy-two-hour refit, and no one's to leave the ship during that time. I repeat, all planet leave is canceled. I've just had an unhappy love affair, so I don't see why anybody else should have a good time. Message ends.</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Prostetnic Vogon Jeltz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>